Guide to the Bingham Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Hiram Bingham III, Latin America, 1842-1930; Series V; 11.75; (28 boxes)
  - Writings
    - "The Scots Darien Company"
      - Research notes, chapters 1-17 (Box 38, Folder 37-38)
      - Research notes: "The Edinburgh Gazette" (Box 38, Folder 39-41)
      - Research notes (Box 39, Folder 42-63)
      - Illustrations (Box 39, Folder 64)
    - "Causes of Lack of Political Cohesion in South America", 1910 November (Box 40, Folder 65)
    - "Certain Characteristics of the South Americans of Today", 1910 December (Box 40, Folder 65)
    - "Potosi", 1911 January (Box 40, Folder 66)
    - "The Monroe Doctrine: An Obsolete Shibboleth"
      - TMs drafts, preface, chapters 1-10, 1913 (Box 40, Folder 67-70)
      - Research notes (Box 40, Folder 71-75)
    - "The Economic Future of the West Coast of South America", 1914 January (Box 40, Folder 76)
    - "Should We Abandon the Monroe Doctrine?", 1914 January (Box 40, Folder 76)
    - "The Latin American Attitude toward the Monroe Doctrine", 1914 April (Box 40, Folder 76)
    - "Latin America and the Monroe Doctrine", 1914 July (Box 40, Folder 77)
    - "The Probable Effect of the Opening of the Panama Canal on Our Economic Relations with the People of the West Coast of South America", 1914 July (Box 40, Folder 78)
    - "The Monroe Doctrine for the Caribbean", 1917 April (Box 40, Folder 78)
    - "The Future of The Monroe Doctrine", 1920 April (Box 40, Folder 79)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Panama notes, 1901-1904 (Box 40, Folder 80)
    - Photographs of Panama, Undated (Box 41, Folder 81)
    - Latin America, 1902-1904 (Box 41, Folder 82)
    - Brazil, 1907 November-1908 December (Box 41, Folder 83)
    - "Brazilian memoranda", 1853-1905 (Box 42, Folder 83a-85)
    - "Brazilian memoranda", 1906 (Box 43, Folder 86)
    - Views of South America: Index, 1906-1907 (Box 43, Folder 87)
    - Views of South America, 1906-1907 (Box 43, Folder 88-90)
    - Views of South America, 1906-1907 (Box 44, Folder 91-99)
    - Views of South America, 1906-1907 (Box 45, Folder 100-102)
    - Photos of Venezuela and Colombia, 1906-1907 (Box 45, Folder 103)
    - List of photos of Venezuela, Undated (Box 45, Folder 104)
    - Clippings on Venezuela
      - 1907-1908 (Box 45, Folder 105)
      - 1908-1909 (Box 46, Folder 106-108)
      - 1909 (Box 47, Folder 109)
    - Clippings on South America
      - 1906-1913 (Box 47, Folder 110)
      - 1907-1908 (Box 48, Folder 111)
    - Clippings on South American trade, 1907-1908 (Box 48, Folder 112-113)
    - Clippings on South America, 1912-1917 (Box 48, Folder 114-115)
    - Clippings relating to the war between Chile and Peru, 1885 December-1886 April (Box 48A)
    - Clippings on South America, Circa 1903 (Box 48A)
  - Pan-American Conferences
    - Pan-American Congress
      - Invitation and documents, 1913-1916 (Box 49, Folder 116)
      - Reports, 1908-1915 (Box 49, Folder 117)
      - Bulletins and programs, 1910-1916 (Box 49, Folder 118)
      - Mailing lists, Undated (Box 49, Folder 119)
      - Articles and clippings, 1902-1910 (Box 49, Folder 120)
      - Souvenir buttons, Undated (Box 49, Folder 121)
    - Pan-American Day at Yale
      - Correspondence, 1915-1916 (Box 49, Folder 122)
      - Instructions for delegates and student reception committee, 1916 (Box 49, Folder 123)
      - Printed matter regarding Yale and New Haven, 1916 (Box 49, Folder 124)
      - Clippings, 1916 January-February (Box 49, Folder 125)
  - Reference file
    - Argentina
      - Research notes, articles, 1907-1908 (Box 49, Folder 126)
      - Pamphlets, 1909-1916 (Box 49, Folder 127)
      - Newsclippings, 1907-1908 (Box 49, Folder 128)
      - Biografia de Rosas, [1842] (Box 49, Folder 129)
    - Bolivia
      - Research notes, Undated (Box 49, Folder 130)
      - Articles, 1902-1909 (Box 50, Folder 131)
      - Pamphlets, 1905-1944 (Box 50, Folder 132)
      - Printed materials, Undated (Box 50, Folder 133)
      - Newsclippings, 1907-1909 (Box 50, Folder 134)
    - Brazil
      - Research Notes, Undated (Box 50, Folder 135)
      - Articles, 1902-1912 (Box 50, Folder 136)
      - Pamphlets, 1906 (Box 50, Folder 137)
      - Pamphlets by Joaquim Nabuco, 1909 (Box 50, Folder 138)
      - Book, 1909 (Box 50, Folder 139)
      - Trade articles, 1908 (Box 50, Folder 140)
      - Newsclippings, 1910-1912 (Box 50, Folder 141)
    - Canal Zone: pamphlets, 1912 (Box 50, Folder 142)
    - Central America
      - Articles, maps, 1908 (Box 50, Folder 143)
      - Research notes, correspondence, 1910 (Box 50, Folder 144)
      - Pamphlets, 1912 (Box 50, Folder 145)
      - Newsclippings, 1907-1908 (Box 50, Folder 146)
    - Chile
      - Research notes, Undated (Box 51, Folder 147)
      - Articles, 1891-1909 (Box 51, Folder 148)
      - Pamphlets, 1911 (Box 51, Folder 149)
      - Newsclippings, 1908 (Box 51, Folder 150)
    - Colombia
      - Research notes, Undated (Box 51, Folder 151)
      - Articles: Travel Letters from W. Wheeler, 1923 (Box 51, Folder 152)
      - Articles (Box 51, Folder 153)
      - Pamphlets, clippings, 1907-1909 (Box 51, Folder 154)
    - Costa Rica: articles, newsclippings, 1910-1912 (Box 51, Folder 155)
    - Cuba: research notes, Undated (Box 51, Folder 156)
    - Cuba: articles, pamphlets, newsclippings, 1906-1912 (Box 51, Folder 157)
    - Ecuador: research notes, articles, newsclippings, 1907-1908 (Box 51, Folder 158)
    - Falkland Islands: articles, 1907-1908 (Box 51, Folder 159)
    - French West Indies: articles, newsclippings, 1908-1909 (Box 51, Folder 160)
    - Guatemala: research notes, newsclippings, 1907-1910 (Box 51, Folder 161)
    - Haiti, Honduras: research notes, articles, newsclippings, 1875-1908 (Box 51, Folder 162)
    - Jamaica: research notes, articles, map, 1907-1908 (Box 51, Folder 163)
    - Latin America
      - Research notes, 1908-1913 (Box 51, Folder 164)
      - Articles, 1908-1910, undated (Box 51, Folder 165-166)
      - Pamphlets, 1887-1930, undated (Box 52, Folder 167-169)
      - Newsclippings, 1902-1915 (Box 52, Folder 170-171)
    - Mexico
      - Research notes, Undated (Box 52, Folder 172)
      - Articles, 1870-1910 (Box 52, Folder 173-174)
      - Pamphlets, 1909 (Box 52, Folder 175)
      - Newsclippings, 1907-1910 (Box 52, Folder 176)
      - Un Siglo de Relaciones Internacionales de Mexico, 1878-1910 (Box 53, Folder 177)
    - Nicaragua: articles, newsclippings, 1878-1910 (Box 53, Folder 178)
    - Panama
      - Research notes, articles, 1905-1909 (Box 53, Folder 179)
      - Pamphlets, 1907-1912 (Box 53, Folder 180)
      - Newsclippings, 1903-1912 (Box 53, Folder 181-184)
    - Pan America: pamphlets, newsclippings, 1907-1908 (Box 53, Folder 185)
    - Paraguay
      - Research notes, Undated (Box 53, Folder 186)
      - Articles, pamphlets, newsclippings, 1904-1908 (Box 53, Folder 187)
    - Peru
      - Research notes, Undated (Box 53, Folder 188)
      - Articles, newsclippings, 1908-1914 (Box 53, Folder 189)
      - El Arte Peruano En La Escuela I, II, Circa 1926 (Box 53, Folder 190)
    - Philippines
      - Research notes, 1910 (Box 54, Folder 191)
      - Articles, pamphlets, 1904-1910 (Box 54, Folder 192)
    - Salvador: articles, 1908 (Box 54, Folder 193)
    - San Martin: research notes, newsclippings, 1909 (Box 54, Folder 194)
    - Santo Domingo: articles, newsclippings, 1908-1909 (Box 54, Folder 194)
    - Spain
      - Research notes, Undated (Box 54, Folder 195)
      - Articles, 1874-1911 (Box 54, Folder 196)
      - Pamphlets, newsclippings, 1909-1911 (Box 54, Folder 197)
    - Trinidad: articles, 1908 (Box 54, Folder 198)
    - West Indies: research notes, articles, 1908 (Box 54, Folder 198)
    - Uruguay: research notes, articles, 1908-1911 (Box 54, Folder 199)
    - Venezuela
      - Research notes, Undated (Box 54, Folder 200)
      - Articles, newsclippings, 1908-1910 (Box 54, Folder 201)
    - Bibliography, Undated (Box 54, Folder 202-203)
    - Bibliography of Hiram Bingham III's books on Latin America, 1908-1913 (Box 54, Folder 204)
    - Manuscript articles not by Hiram Bingham III, 1909-1910, undated (Box 54, Folder 205-206)
    - Manuscript articles with critiques by Hiram Bingham III, 1893-1916 (Box 54, Folder 207)
    - Note cards
      - Place names in Peru (Box 55, Folder 208)
      - Place names in Peru (Box 56, Folder 209)
      - Name cards (Box 56, Folder 210)
      - Card address list (Box 56, Folder 211)
      - Yale Peruvian Expedition (Box 57, Folder 212)
      - Yale Peruvian Expedition (Box 58, Folder 213)
      - Yale Peruvian Expedition (Box 59, Folder 214)
      - Yale Peruvian Expedition (Box 60, Folder 215)
      - Bibliography-Yale Peruvian Expedition (Box 61, Folder 216)
      - Place names in Peru (Box 61, Folder 217)
      - Map cards and date file (Box 61, Folder 218)
      - Books (Box 62, Folder 219)
      - Index-bibliography (Box 62, Folder 220)
      - Index-bibliography (Box 63, Folder 221)
      - Chronology (Box 63, Folder 222)
- Hiram Bingham III, War service and aviation, 1914-1943; Series VI; 3.25; (8 boxes)
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically. All other sections arranged by type of material, then chronologically.
  Series VI, Hiram Bingham III, War service and aviation, contains materials regarding Bingham's military activities, 1916-1918, and his interest in aviation. The first section, Correspondence, relates primarily to his service at the Connecticut National Guard encampment in Pennsylvania (1916), with a few letters dated 1917 January-1919 January. Company records consists of military orders, printed matter, and other papers related to the National Guard encampment. Financial records consists of vouchers, journals, receipts, and other financial papers of the National Guard during 1916. Marshall Foch's visit to Yale consists of newsclippings, a scrapbook, and accounts of Foch's visit in November 1921, by Hiram, Alfreda, and Woodbridge Bingham. The final section, Aviation, consists of materials relating to Bingham's service with the A.E.F., 1917-1918, and his involvement in aviation organizations and government committees dealing with aviation affairs from 1918 to 1935. This material includes some correspondence, lists of complimentary copies, photographs, and a scrapbook concerning his book, An Explorer in the Air Service (1920), but no manuscripts of the book. Many of his published articles about aviation, 1916-1934, are also contained in this section. Papers relating to the Air Service, American Expeditionary Force, 1917-1918, include reports, manuals, charts, notes, and bulletins. Other aviation materials include periodicals, newsclippings, scrapbooks, reports, and printed matter, dated 1914-1943.
  - Correspondence, 1916 July-1919 Jan, undated (Box 64, Folder 1-9)
  - Company records
    - Military and Company orders
      - 1916 June-September 20 (Box 64, Folder 10-13)
      - 1916 September 21-Dec, undated (Box 65, Folder 14-16)
      - Documents and forms: blanks (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - Commissions, certificates, and awards (oversize) (Folder 114)
    - Officers' Mess, 1916 July-September (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - Personnel, 1916 (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - Inventory, 1916 (Box 65, Folder 20)
    - Printed matter
      - Camp newspapers, 1916 Aug, undated (Box 65, Folder 21)
      - Regimental Battery book, 1916-1917 (Box 65, Folder 22)
      - Miscellaneous, 1915-1924 (Box 65, Folder 23)
  - Financial records
    - Individual vouchers, Series A-C, 1916 (Box 65, Folder 24-26)
    - Business vouchers, 1916 (Box 65, Folder 27)
    - Receipts and expenditures journal, 1916 July 17-November 16 (Box 65, Folder 28)
    - Officers' Mess journal, 1916 July 22-September 19 (Box 66, Folder 29)
    - Wages journal, 1916 July 31-November 15 (Box 66, Folder 30)
    - Wages ledger, 1916 June 19-September 21 (Box 66, Folder 31)
    - Yale Battalion Fathers' Fund statements, 1916 July-September (Box 66, Folder 32)
    - Yale Battalion Fathers' Fund journal, 1916 July 1-November 23 (Box 66, Folder 33)
    - Fathers' and Alumni Fund journal, 1916 July 3-September 27 (Box 66, Folder 34)
    - Cancelled checks (Box 66, Folder 35)
    - Cash record, 1916 July 8-September 27 (Box 66, Folder 36)
    - Record of Officers' Mess, 1916 June-September (Box 66, Folder 36)
    - Vouchers: General Mess Fund, Series A, 1916 July 7-November 15 (Box 67, Folder 37)
    - Vouchers, 1916 August 28-November 6 (Box 67, Folder 38)
    - Record of vouchers, 1916 July 31-September 22 (Box 67, Folder 39)
    - Receipts
      - Quartermaster Corps, U.S. Army, 1916 July 17-September 13 (Box 67, Folder 40)
      - T.M. Lynch & Bros., Merchants, 1916 August-September (Box 67, Folder 41)
      - 1916 June 30-July 20 (Box 67, Folder 42)
      - 1916 July 21-31 (Box 67, Folder 43)
      - 1916 August 1-15 (Box 67, Folder 44)
      - 1916 August 16-31 (Box 67, Folder 45)
      - 1916 September 1-15 (Box 67, Folder 46)
      - 1916 September 16-30 (Box 67, Folder 47)
      - 1916 October-December (Box 67, Folder 48)
  - Marshall Foch's visit to Yale
    - Accounts of visit by Hiram Bingham III, Alfreda Bingham, Woodbridge Bingham, 1921 November 14-17 (Box 68, Folder 49)
    - Newsclippings, 1921 (Box 68, Folder 50)
    - Scrapbook, 1921 (Box 68, Folder 51)
  - Aviation
    - An Explorer in the Air Service
      - Correspondence, 1920 November 23-1922 April 28 (Box 68, Folder 52)
      - Lists of complimentary copies sent (Box 68, Folder 53)
      - Printed matter and photographs (Box 68, Folder 54)
      - Scrapbook, 1920-1922 (Box 68, Folder 55)
    - Articles by Hiram Bingham III, 1916-1918 (Box 68, Folder 56)
    - Articles by Hiram Bingham III, 1920-1934 (Box 69, Folder 57)
    - Notes, 1920 (Box 69, Folder 58)
    - Air Service, American Expeditionary Force
      - Reports and manuals, 1917-1918 (Box 69, Folder 59)
      - Charts and graphs, Undated (Box 69, Folder 60)
      - Notes on rank and procedure, 1917 (Box 69, Folder 61)
      - Schools Division, 1917 November (Box 69, Folder 62)
      - Regulations-U.S. Schools of Military Aeronautics, 1918 (Box 69, Folder 62a)
      - Bulletin of the Information Section, 1918 June-August (Box 69, Folder 63-64)
    - Third Aviation Instruction Center, American Expeditionary Force: administrative notes, flight charts and instructions, 1918 September-December (Box 69, Folder 65-66)
    - Newsclippings: "Plane News", 1918 August-1919 April (Box 69, Folder 67-72)
    - Newsclippings, 1914-1931, undated (Box 69, Folder 73)
    - Scrapbook, 1925-1930 (Box 70, Folder 74-75)
    - Government reports, 1918, 1923, 1935 (Box 71, Folder 76)
    - Non-government reports, 1917, 1942-1943 (Box 71, Folder 77)
    - Magazines, 1917-1934 (Box 71, Folder 78)
    - The Aviation Pocket-Book, 1917 (Box 71, Folder 79)
    - Printed matter, 1918-1924 (Box 71, Folder 80)
- Hiram Bingham III, Politics, 1901-1935; Series VII; 7.5; (17 boxes)
  Speeches and essays, Published speeches and articles, Newsclippings, and Scrapbooks are each arranged chronologically. National Hughes Alliance is arranged by type of material. Connecticut state politics and Printed matter are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Series VII, Hiram Bingham III, Politics, consists of papers relating to Bingham's political activities, including his service as Lieutenant Governor and Governor of Connecticut and as United States Senator. There are relatively few papers from this period--and also very little correspondence (Series III) relating to his political career. The first section in this series, Speeches and essays, consists of manuscripts of Bingham's political writings, 1922-1935; a small speech reference file; and background articles. Published speeches and articles consists of writings, 1922-1934; Bingham's remarks in the Congressional Record, 1925-1929; and campaign literature about Bingham. Newsclippings about Hiram Bingham III consists of newspaper articles and notices from 1923 to 1935, with some general clippings dated 1917-1935. Scrapbooks consists of volumes documenting Bingham's political career and interests from 1919 to 1935. The fifth section, National Hughes Alliance, contains papers relating to Bingham's activities as head of the 1916 Republican presidential campaign in Connecticut, including a large file of Hughes Alliance membership cards giving the name, address, and occupation of members. Connecticut state politics consists of legislative manuals and bills, state government reports, market bulletins, and other papers on selected subjects and on several towns in the state. The final section, Printed matter, consists of campaign literature, dinner programs, government reports and publications, and printed matter relating to foreign affairs, particularly regarding the Dominican Republic, Mexico, and Nicaragua. There are also papers concerning the National Economic League, and Bingham's annotated copy of Josiah Royce's The Hope of the Great Community (1916).
  - Speeches and Essays
    - 1922 May-1935 (Box 72, Folder 1-7)
    - Undated speeches (Box 72, Folder 8-9)
    - Notes (Box 72, Folder 10-11)
    - Speech reference file
      - Calvin Coolidge (Box 72, Folder 12)
      - Warren G. Harding (Box 72, Folder 13)
      - Child labor (Box 72, Folder 14)
      - Sheppard-Towner bill (Box 72, Folder 15)
      - Nicaragua (Box 72, Folder 16)
      - Highway advertising (Box 72, Folder 17)
      - Taxation (Box 72, Folder 18)
      - Political platforms (Box 72, Folder 19)
      - Forestry (Box 72, Folder 20)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 73, Folder 21-22)
    - Background articles, 1923-1924 (Box 73, Folder 23-24)
  - Published speeches and articles
    - 1922-1934 (Box 73, Folder 25-27)
    - Congressional Record, 1925 January 19-1929 October 9 (Box 73, Folder 28-31)
    - Campaign literature (Box 73, Folder 32)
  - Newsclippings about Hiram Bingham III
    - 1923-1935, undated (Box 74, Folder 33-42)
    - General (not about HB III), 1917-1935 (Box 74, Folder 43)
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1919 October-1925 April (Box 74, Folder 44)
    - Calvin Coolidge, 1923-1932 (Box 75, Folder 45)
    - 1921 September-1924 August (Box 75, Folder 46)
    - 1924 (Box 76, Folder 47-48)
    - Far East, 1927 February-December (Box 76, Folder 49)
    - 1927-1929 (Box 77, Folder 50-52)
    - 1930-1931 June (Box 78, Folder 53-54)
    - Oversize, 1920-1928 (Box 79, Folder 55-56)
    - 1932 July-December (Box 80, Folder 57)
  - National Hughes Alliance
    - Constitution and membership lists, 1916 (Box 80, Folder 58)
    - Printed matter, 1916 (Box 80, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence, stationery, publicity, 1916 (Box 80, Folder 60)
    - Hughes Alliance membership cards, 1916 (Box 81, Folder 61)
    - Hughes Alliance membership cards, 1916 (Box 82, Folder 62)
    - Hughes Alliance membership cards, 1916 (Box 83, Folder 63)
    - Hughes Alliance membership cards, 1916 (Box 84, Folder 64)
    - Hughes Alliance membership cards, 1916 (Box 85, Folder 65)
  - Connecticut state politics
    - Athletics Commission, Undated (Box 86, Folder 66)
    - Automobiles, 1912-1914 (Box 86, Folder 66)
    - Connecticut Market Bulletins, 1924 November-December (Box 86, Folder 67)
    - Connecticut Tercentenary, 1935 (Box 86, Folder 68)
    - Legislation, 1923 (Box 86, Folder 69)
    - Legislative manual and bills, 1923 (Box 86, Folder 70)
    - Legislative memoranda, 1916-1925 (Box 86, Folder 71)
    - Reports on farms, 1922 July-1923 June (Box 86, Folder 72)
    - Sewing room report, 1922 July-1923 June (Box 86, Folder 72)
    - Reports on health
      - Connecticut Infirmary Commission, 1923 February 1 (Box 86, Folder 73)
      - Connecticut State Hospital, 1924 June 30 (Box 86, Folder 73)
      - Connecticut Workmen's Compensation and Employers' Liability Acts, 1913 (Box 86, Folder 73)
    - Reports on highways, 1923-1924 (Box 86, Folder 74)
    - Report on Public Utilities Commission, 1924 (Box 86, Folder 75)
    - Report on tax exemptions, 1923 June 4 (Box 86, Folder 76)
    - Towns
      - A-Ne (Box 86, Folder 77)
      - Norwich (Box 86, Folder 78-79)
      - Salem (Box 86, Folder 80)
      - Salisbury-South Coventry (Box 86, Folder 81)
  - Printed matter
    - Campaign literature: national, 1916-1924 (Box 87, Folder 82)
    - Campaign literature: Republican National Conventions, 1916, 1928, 1932 (Box 87, Folder 83)
    - Dinner programs, 1924, 1932 (Box 87, Folder 84)
    - Foreign affairs
      - Government reports, 1923-1930 (Box 87, Folder 85-87)
      - Non-government reports, 1924-1927 (Box 87, Folder 88)
      - Dominican Republic, 1901, 1920, 1926 (Box 87, Folder 89)
      - Mexico, 1917-1920 (Box 87, Folder 90)
      - Mexico, 1926-1927 (Box 88, Folder 91)
      - Nicaragua, 1902-1928 (Box 88, Folder 92-93)
    - Government publications, 1915-1929 (Box 88, Folder 94-95)
    - The National Economic League, 1916 (Box 88, Folder 96)
    - Josiah Royce, The Hope of the Great Community, 1916 (Box 88, Folder 97)
- Hiram Bingham III, Elihu Yale biography, 1671-1939; 1937-1939; Series VIII; 3; (7 boxes)
  Writings by Hiram Bingham III is arranged chronologically. The other sections in the series are arranged by type of material and by subject.
  Series VIII, Hiram Bingham III, Elihu Yale biography, consists of materials relating to Bingham's research and writing about the early benefactor of Yale College. The first section, Writings of Hiram Bingham III, consists of printed editions of his two articles about Elihu Yale, drafts of one of these articles, and drafts, photographs, and illustrations for his book, Elihu Yale, the American Nabob of Queen Square (1939). Research material includes photostatic copies of India Office documents, records from the British Museum and other repositories, and printed articles and other materials relating to Yale. The final section, Research notes, includes Bingham's notes on various subjects relating to Yale's life. Notes filed under the heading "Elihu Yale chronology" were arranged by year, but Bingham's headings do not always correspond with the dates of materials in the folders. This section also contains maps, research correspondence, a bibliography, and other reference material.
  - Writings of Hiram Bingham III
    - "Elihu Yale, the American Nabob of Queen Square", 1938 June (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - "Elihu Yale: Governor, Collector and Benefactor", 1938 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - "Elihu Yale: Governor, Collector and Benefactor": preliminary and partial drafts, 1938 (Box 89, Folder 3-5)
    - Elihu Yale, the American Nabob of Queen Square
      - First and second drafts, 1939 (Box 89, Folder 6-10)
      - Manuscript draft, 1939 (Box 90, Folder 11-16)
      - Lists of photographs and illustrations, 1939 (Box 90, Folder 17)
      - Photographs and illustrations, 1939 (Box 90, Folder 18-19)
      - Photographs: The Wallace Collection, 1939 (Box 90, Folder 20)
    - Research material
      - Elihu Yale's diary, 1681-1682; India Office documents (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 21-22)
      - Correspondence, Thomas Pitt to Elihu Yale, 1700-1709; British Museum (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 23-24)
      - Charges against Governor Yale (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 25)
      - Abstract of charges against Elihu Yale (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 26)
      - Charges made against Elihu Yale (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 27)
      - Yale papers; British Museum (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 28-30)
      - Yale papers (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 31)
      - Yale family wills (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 32)
      - Articles relating to Elihu Yale's gift to the College (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 33)
      - Articles on Wrexham (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 34)
      - India Office documents (photostatic copies) (Box 91, Folder 35-37)
      - India Office correspondence (photostatic copies) (Box 92, Folder 38-40)